When I was going through my wardrobe
我收拾衣柜的时候
I found an extra hairpin on the floor
在地板上我发现了一个多余的发夹
That's nothing, I found her hair in my bed.
那不算什么，我还在床上发现了她的头发
Just another tragedy of a down-and-out, I guess
我想，那只是另一出心力交瘁的悲剧，
For I'm selling the thing
我所卖出的东西
That means every thing to my life...
代表了我的生命和我的幸福的一切...
Some women bring happines...
有的女人，她们走到哪儿，欢乐就跟到哪儿；
wherever they go.Others, whenever they go.
有些，则是及时行乐
I do both.
我二者兼顾
Husbands like tosee me come...
丈夫们乐意看到我来，
wives prefer to seeme go.
妻子们则喜欢送我走
There she is.That's her.
她在那，那就是她
Whose husband didn't she sleep with?
她谁的丈夫没睡过啊?
- Who's she with now?- Who knows.
- 她现在跟谁在一起啊?- 谁知道
- She's older than I thought.- Look. Watch.
- 她比我想的老- 看，看好
This will teach her.
这会给她个教训
I'm sorry, Mrs Erlynne, but that account was closed.
对不起，Erlynne太太,但是那个账户已经
By Mrs Fairchild.
被Fairchild太太停了
I wish you'd told me before I ordered the Bordeaux.
我希望你在我点Bordeaux酒之前告诉我就好了
What Bordeaux, Mrs Erlynne?
什么Bordeaux酒, Erlynne太太?
Joe, you're my kind of guy.
Joe, 你是我喜欢的那类男人
- Is she behind me?- In the blue.
- 她在我后面吗?- 穿兰色衣服
Charge it to Senator Kleghorn.
那就算在Kleghorn参议员的帐上吧
That's Mrs Kleghorn sitting next to Mrs Fairchild.
Fairchild太太边上坐的就是Kleghorn太太
- What a small world.- And Mrs Winters on her right.
- 世界可真小啊- 她左边的是Winters太太
And getting smaller.
哦，越来越小了
You wanna go outthe back?
你要从后面走吗?
No, if you go out the back, you'll never come in the front, Joe.
不，如果你从后门走就再也别想从前面进来了，Joe
A lady always leaves the way she came.
淑女怎么来，便怎么走
I thought my husband had more taste.
你看看她，我以为我丈夫更有品呢
So sorry to hear you're leaving us, Mrs Erlynne.
听说你要走真难过，Erlynne太太
- I'm leaving you?- I'll prepare your bill.
我要退房？- 我给您备好账单
I ask you to make me an offer
我让你开个价，
I don't know how much it will bring
我不知道那会值多少
It isn't a lot...
虽然那并不算太多
but it's all I've got
但那已经倾我所有
Pooled by an old gold ring?
把老金戒也一起卖了？
It's known me as poor as a beggar
有时我一贫如洗，象个乞丐
And it's known me as rich as a king
有时我挥金如土，象个国王
And it's known me in hell And in heaven as well
我既下过地狱，又上过天堂
Pooled by an old gold ring?
把老金戒也一起卖了？
My sudden changeing circumstance...
我环境的突变...
was not the only reason for my departure.
并不是我离开的唯一理由
The italian coast in summerattracts the rich and famous.
夏季的意大利海滩吸引着富者和名人
I'm infamous and poor.
我没名气又穷
Close enough.
挺接近的
One door closes,another opens.
一扇门关闭，另一扇开启了
Sometimes that door isnot the one you expect.
有时那并不是你所期待的门
I saw my chance anddecided to take it.
我看到了我的机会并决定抓住
Meg, dear. Come along.Come along.
Meg, 亲爱的，快过来
Ah, Giuseppina.
啊, Giuseppina
She's my friend.Give her a discount.
她是我的朋友，给她一个折扣
Come here.
过来
It's the best glove shop in the city.
这是城里最好的手套店
She'll give you a good discount.
她会给你个好折扣
You go along, I'll find yourhusband, don't worry.
你去吧，我会找到你丈夫的，别担心
This way, madam.
这边请，女士
These are pretty.
这真漂亮
- Your hand looks about right.- I beg your pardon?
- 你的手看上去差不多- 你说什么?
My little sister. She wasadamant about every detail but...
我的小妹妹，她把细节都说了...
neglected to tell me the size.Would you mind?
就是忘了告诉我尺码，你介意吗?
Oh, no, of course not.
不，当然不会
It's always a little snugthe first time.
第一次有点挤
Maybe you should takeoff your ring.
也许你该退去戒指
It's my wedding ring,I never take it off.
那是我的结婚戒指，我不能把它拿下来
The other hand, then.
那，就另一只手吧
No need to button it. You can seeit fits perfectly.
不要系扣，你能看出来很合手的
Lord Darlington,you depraved man.
Darlington大人，你这个堕落的人
What have you been up to?
你打算干什么啊?
Ignore him, Meg, dear.He's a great sinner.
别理他, Meg, 亲爱的他可是个大罪人
But an excellent bridge partner.
可却是个了不起的桥梁合伙人
Or I would never tolerate him.
要不我肯定会忍受不了他的
- Do you know each other?- The year I spent in the London office.
- 你们彼此认识了吗?- 在伦敦办事处的那年认识的
I told you about John.But you've met.
我跟你提过John但，你们已经认识了吧
- No. It's nice to meet you.- It's a pleasure, Mrs Windemere.
- 没有，认识你很荣幸- 很荣幸，Windemere太太
Your wife was helping me selectgloves for my mother.
你太太正帮我给我母亲选手套
- Your sister, you said.- Either one.
- 你妹妹，你说的- 两个人的
We should have dinner.Where are you staying?
我们该一起用餐你们住哪?
The Grand, but we're tryingto find a villa.
住Grand,但我们正在找别墅
So late in the season.I warned you.
在这个季节有点晚了，我警告过你的
I know one that's available.
我知道一个合适的
Isn't it an election year inthe wild west?
今年是狂野西部的竞选年吧?
Who says I'm running?
谁说我参选了?
- It's perfect. It's beaultiful.- Did I mention the ghost?
- 真完美，太美了- 我提到鬼魂了吗?
I feel like a princessin a fairly tale.
我能想到的都在这了我觉得自己象童话中的公主
You are a princess.
你就是公主
That's because Imarried the prince.
那是因为我嫁给了王子
I have her completely fooled,poor girl.
我把她完全骗住了，可怜的女孩
If I could fool a woman aspretty, I wouldn't be a bachelor.
如果我能骗到一个象你太太一样漂亮的女孩我就不会仍是单身汉了
- Now you've made her blush.- Don't be silly.
- 看你让她不好意思了- 别傻了
Come and see the paintings.
来看看画吧
Come on.
走
Good evening.
晚上好
Lady Plymdale?
Plymdale女士？
Oh, is she the onewith the big...
哦，她就是那个有大...
Feet. Enourmous feet.Poor old Plymdale.
脚，著名的大脚可怜的老Plymdale
- Ace, Queen, King, Jack.- No honours.
- A, Q, K ，J- 真没面子
No, no, John's yacht,John's rules.
不，John的游艇John的规矩
- Have it.- Thank you.
- 拿去- 谢谢你
Huge feet. Pontoons.
大脚，浮桥
If desire had an antidote, it wouldbe those pontoons of hers.
如果期待能够修正，那就是她的浮桥了
I grow ill thinking of then.
我想的都得病了
How many times have youbeen divorced, Tuppy?
你离过多少次婚了, Tuppy?
- Three, four? I've simply lost count.- That's bigamy.
- 三次，四次? 我不会数了- 那是重婚
Bigamy is having one wifetoo many.
重婚是有过多妻子
So is monogamy
那是一夫一妻
One should always have a properbasis for marriage. A mutual...
每个人都该有个合理的婚姻基础一个相互……
- Misunderstanding?- Exactly.
- 误解?- 没错
A man can't be happywith one woman.
男人只有一个女人是不会快乐的
A man can be happy with any woman.As long as he doesn't love her.
只要不爱，男人跟任何女人都会快乐
For a man who's never thoughtof getting married...
对于一个永不言婚的男人来说...
you seem to know an awfullot about it.
你知道的够多的
I've thought very seriously of marrying.That's why I'm still single.
我对婚姻考虑甚为周详所以至今未婚
Hear, hear.
听到了
I just haven't met the right woman.Look at Cecil, still with Edna.
我只是还没遇到合适的看Cecil, 还跟Edna在一起
One keeps one's eyes wide openbefore the wedding...
一个人该在婚礼前大睁双眼...
and half shut after.
其后就要睁一眼闭一眼了
- That's all there is to it.- Exactly.
- 就那么回事- 没错
I fancy raising the stakes.
我想结束了
Oh, lucky blighter!
哦，幸运的家伙
You don't look as ifyou're enjoying yourself.
你看着不怎么开心啊
Oh, I am. It's a verynice party.
哦，我开心，晚会很好
- Can I get you a drink?- No, thank you. I don't drink.
- 我能给你拿个饮品么?- 不了，谢谢，我不喝
You don't drink?
你不喝?
- Do I seem like a prig?- No, of course not.
- 我看上去象个假正经的人吗?- 不，当然不是
- It's the way I was raised.- In a convent?
- 我就是那样被带大的- 在修道院吗?
By my Aunt Julia.My father's sister.
是我的Julia姑姑我父亲的姐姐
My mother died when Iwas very little.
我幼年丧母
It's the only picture Ihave of her.
这是我有的她唯一的照片
My father never remarried.
我父亲从没再婚
She's every bit as beaultifulas her daughter.
她似她女儿般美貌
Have I offended you?I meant it as a compliment.
我冒犯你了吗?我是在恭维你呢
- You pay me too many compliments.- I'll stop at once.
- 你过于恭维我了- 我会马上停止
- Thank you.- Just so you know, I meant every one.
- 谢谢你- 你只要知道，我是真心的
You pretend to be bad, but...
你假装坏，但...
- you're not really.- There is no good or bad.
- 其实你不是- 没有好坏之分
People are either charmingor tedious.
人只有迷人和沉闷之分
If I've been the latter,I sincerely apologize.
如果我是后者，我真诚道歉
- I'd like us to become friends.- We already are, aren't we?
- 我希望我们能成朋友- 我们已经是了，对吧?
Not if you keep flattering me andpaying me silly compliments.
那就别奉承我或是说些愚蠢的恭维话
Define silly.
定义“愚蠢”
I want your word.
你得保证
I find the best way to keep myword is never to give it.
我发现要想不食言就别乱保证
It's always a pleasureto see a pretty woman.
看到漂亮女人永远都是一种荣幸
Good day.
天气不错
It has to be somethingreally special...
一定得是特别的东西...
My wife's birthday.
是我妻子的生日
This is a very specialobject.
这个非常特别
What do you think?
你觉得怎么样?
The sapphire matches your eyes.
蓝宝石很衬你的眼睛
It's for my wife.
是给我妻子的
A man should never buy hiswife jewellery.
男人可不该给妻子买珠宝
And why is that?
那是为什么?
It makes her wonder whathe bought his mistress.
那会让她猜测他会给情妇买什么
My wife has nothing towonder about.
我妻子没什么可猜测的
She's a lucky woman.
她是个幸运的女人
If I was your wife...
如果我是你妻子...
- this is what I'd want.- A fan?
- 这才是我想要的- 一把扇子?
Not for stirring the air,for stirring the heart.
不为鼓动空气，为了鼓动心灵
For centuries...
是经历百年...
an erotic language betweenmen an women.
男女间的性欲语言
If a woman placed it on her breastlike this, it meant "I love you".
如果女人把它这样放在胸前那意思是“我爱你”
"When can I see you?"
"我几时能见你?"
"Wait for me."
"等我"
"You may kiss me."
"你可以亲吻我"
"We're being watched."
"我们正被监视"
I'm sold.
我被出卖了
How much?
多少钱?
No, it's not for sale.
不，那个不是卖品
Not for sale.
非卖品？
It would break mymom's heart.
那会伤透我妈妈的心
My mama.
我妈妈
Real gold.
真金的
If you give him everything, who'sgoing to buy me an espresso?
如果你倾囊而出谁给我买浓缩咖啡啊?
My back.
我的后背啊
And Americans everywhere.
而且到处都是美国人
You'd never know there was adepression in that country.
你根本不会知道他们国家正经历经济危机
Please, something to drinkbefore I faint.
拜托，我晕倒前喝点东西吧
They don't shop, they pillage.
他们不是买东西，他们在掠夺
And they speak loudly.
而且他们说话声音太吵
Could the entire nation behard of hearing?
难道他们整个民族都有听力障碍吗?
Something in the diet, perhaps?
可能是吃的东西有问题，也许?
But we have Americanfriends, mama.
但是我们有美国朋友啊，妈妈
They don't need to know whatwe say about them.
但他们不需要知道我们是怎么讲究他们的
If everyone knew what everyonesaid of each other...
如果每个人都知道别人背后怎么讲究自己...
there wouldn't be four friendsin the world.
那人生在世不会有超过四个朋友了
I like America.
我喜欢美国
Name me another society that's gonefrom barbarism to decadence...
你找不到一个社会由荒蛮进入颓废
without bothering to create acivilization in between.
都不劳神经历文明时代
Tribute to American efficiency.
全拜美国人所赐
- There's Mr Windemere.- He must join us then.
- Windemere先生在那- 他得加入我们
He can't see you, mama.
他看不见你，妈妈
Who's that with him?
跟他一起的是谁?
Looks like his wife.
好像是他妻子
No, I don't think it is.
不，我看不是
I can't see now.They're getting into the car.
我现在看不见了，他们进车里了
It must be the wife if she'sgetting into the car.
如果她进车里肯定是他妻子
It wasn't her.
不是的
Then I must know who it is.
那我就得知道到底是谁
I think we should mind ourown business.
我觉得我们该管自己的事
My own business bores me.
我自己的事太无聊了
I much prefer other people's.
我更喜欢管别人闲事
Poor little Meg,she's so sweet.
可怜的Meg，她多可爱
And the girl has no mother.
而且她没妈妈
- I want to take her to my breast.- I had a similar thought.
- 我想把她揽在怀里- 我曾有过类似想法
I don't suppose Mr Windemerewould be pleased to hear it.
我猜Windemere先生不会想听到这些
Merital bliss...
神圣的赐福...
is a great burden to placeon two people, Tuppy.
对两个人是巨大的负担, Tuppy
Sometimes a third person isneeded to lighten the load.
有时第三者是摆脱负担的必需
It would seem,Mr Windemere agrees with you.
看起来， Windemere先生是赞许你的
I can guess what you were doing.
我能猜出你干了什么
Shopping for my birthday present?
给我买生日礼物?
I was right.
我对了
What did you get?
你买什么了?
Not a thing. You're too oldfor presents.
什么也没买，你老得不配买礼物
- A hint. A tiny speck of a hint.- You'll have to wait and see.
- 一个提示，一个小不点的提示- 你得等着瞧
- Perfume?- No, stop it.
- 香水?- 不，别猜了
A book of poems?
一本诗集?
A dress?
一件套装?
A crocodile handbag like theone the Contessa has...
一个象女爵爷提的，用小爪子做扣的
with the little claws hangingoff the bottom?
鳄鱼皮的手袋？
No more guessing.
别猜了
Robert?
Promise we won't end up like thoseold married couples...
保证我，我们不会落得跟那些老家伙一样的下场...
sitting opposite each other atdinner with nothing to say.
虽然在吃饭时面对面坐着但无话可谈
You, with nothing to say?
你，无话可谈?
I promise.
我保证
We'll always tell eachother the truth?
我们要一直彼此讲真话?
Except around birthdays.
除了生日
You're feisty.What have you been reading?
你很活跃啊在看什么书?
- What do you mean?- No, it's nice.
- 什么意思?- 没有，挺好
Turn out the lights.
关上灯
- But I like to see you.- Please?
-可我想看你－拜托
I'll take them all.
我都要了
- Good day, madam.- Excuse me.
- 你好，女士- 请原谅
I bought a suit.
我买了一件套装
It's being altered.For Margaret Windemere.
正在改，给Margaret Windemere
Ah, Mrs Windemere.One moment, please.
啊, Windemere太太请稍等
Thank you.
谢谢
Forgive me.You're American, aren't you?
请原谅你是美国人，对吧？
I'm from New York.Mrs Erlynne.
我从New York来，Erlynne太太
Rhode Island.Mrs Windemere.
Rhode 岛，Windemere太太
I need an opinion from here.Now be honesty.
我需要点建议，真心话
Would you wear it?
你会穿它吗?
Well, it doesn't leave muchto the imagination, does it?
这会让人失去想像力，是吧?
That depends on the imagination.Some men have more than others.
那要看有多少想像力，有些男人比其他的多些
I suppose it's certainly immodest.
我觉得肯定不够端庄
Do you think it's vulgar?
你觉得它粗俗吗?
Some people might.
有些人会那么想
Is your husband with you?I'd love a man's opinion.
你丈夫跟你一起来了吗?我需要一个男人的意见
I can tell you.He's very conservative.
我可以告诉你，他很保守
A woman doesn't knowher own husband.
一个女人是不会了解她丈夫的
Oh, I know Robert.We've been married over a year.
哦，我了解 Robert我们都结婚快一年了
A year? Pratically forever.
一年？简直就跟一辈子似的
Here it is, signora.
给你，女士
Oh, thank you.
哦 谢谢
Thank you very much.Come back again to see us.
多谢你，请再光顾
- Goodbye- You're not taking the hat?
- 再见- 你不要帽子吗?
The colour looks perfect on you.Don't you like it?
颜色很合你，你不要吗?
No, I've nowhere to wear it.It's not exactly church on sunday.
不，我没场合戴，周日并不上教堂
Why not?
为什么?
Can you imagine whatpeople would say?
你能想像人们会怎么说吗?
Well, if we're always guided byother people's thoughts...
哦，如果我们总让别人左右我们...
what's the point ofhaving our own?
那还要自己的头脑干什么用呢?
It was nice meeting you,Mrs Ewin.
高兴人士你，Ewin太太
- Erlynne.- Erlynne.
- Erlynne- Erlynne
She was staying in a pensione...
她本来在一个小旅馆...
now she's in a villa afew minutes from the club.
现在她住在离俱乐部几分钟远的别墅里
He's there.
他在那
I can't help seeing him.
我老是看见他
He comes and goes allhours of the day.
他整天来来去去
Of course, in public, she'salways with other men.
当然，在公开场合她总是跟其他男人在一起
She wears nothing butthe latest fashions.
她只穿最新的时装
Somebody must be giving her a verygenerous allowance.
肯定有某人给她很慷慨的资助
Silence!
安静
And she'll have her hand in Tuppy'spocket next, if he doesn't wake up.
如果Tuppy还不清醒过来她就快把手伸进他口袋里了
She's nothing better thana common prostitute.
她不过是个公众的妓女
And Mrs Windemere has no idea?
Windemere太太不知道吗?
None at all.
根本不知道
- I'm sorry.- She must be on the terrace.
- 对不起- 她肯定在露台
I'm sorry, I didn'tmean to frighten you.
对不起，我可不想吓到你
- Yes, you did.- Yes, you did. What's that?
- 可你吓到我了- 没错，那是什么?
I'm making a menu formy birthday party.
我正准备我生日晚会的菜单
What's italian for lobster?
龙虾的意大利文怎么说?
Aragosta.
Aragosta
Very good. Now you've made me hungry.
很好，现在你把我搞的饿起来了
Leave it, come on. Everyone'slunching at the club.
放下吧，我们走所有人都在俱乐部吃饭
Okay. I'll get Robert.
好，我叫上Robert
I thought you agreed not tocall me at home?
我以为你同意不往我家打电话?
How can I seduce you if youalways bring your husband?
你老带着丈夫，我怎么引诱你啊?
Too slow. Come on.
太慢了，走吧
All right.
好吧
Yes, I'll be there.In an hour.
好，我会在一小时到
Okay, in an hour.
好，一小时
It's quitting time.We're going to lunch.
该休息了，我们要去吃饭
Can't, sorry.
不行，对不起
- You're working?- Money never sleeps.
- 你在工作吗?- 钱可不睡觉
Bugger!
该死
All paying jobs absorb...
付钱的工作吸引人
and degrade the mind.
也会使人堕落
You never had a paying job.
你没有付钱的工作
I rest my case.
我在休庭阶段
Cultivated leisure isman's true calling.
有教养的休闲才是男人的去处
- I have to send some telegrams in town.- I'll wait for you.
- 我要进城发电报- 我要等你
I'll be all afternoon.I don't want you to waste the day.
我要一下午，我可不想浪费你一天（支票：给Erlynne太太，400元）
- Do you mind, John?- Do I mind?
- 你介意吗, John?- 我介意?
No, of course not.
不，当然不会
If you have to escort that woman tothe opera, please don't sit with us.
如果你非要护送那女人去看歌剧别跟我们坐一起
Think of Alessandra.
想想Alessandra
Mrs Erlynne has her own seats.
Erlynne 太太有自己的座位
Who pays for them?
谁付的钱?
Her uncle just died.She's come into some money.
她叔叔刚死，有些进项
And Mr Windemere's visits?
Windemere先生的拜访呢?
He's managing her investments,of course.
他当然是在运作她的投资了
You're so fond of gossip.
你太爱嚼舌根了
You don't give the truth a chanceto put its pants on.
根本没给真相一个穿裤子的机会
It's not the truth that's going withoutpants, dear Tuppy.
亲爱的Tuppy，没穿裤子的不是真相
Would you mind not smoking?
你介意别抽烟吗?
Opera makes me feel so romantic.
歌剧让我感觉太浪漫了
Anything too stupid to besaid is sung.
歌唱真是无聊之极
How's that romantic?
有什么浪漫的?
And the women arealways so fleshy!
而且女人也都太肉感了
Excuse me, that's my foot.
对不起，那是我的脚
Right over here?
就在那吗?
What did I tell you?
我怎么跟你说的？
Stop, boy!
别那样，孩子
Fried anchovies and clamsin a bog. Delicious.
沼泽里的炸凤尾鱼配蛤喇美味
Careful, it's hot.
小心，很烫
You told Robert we weregoing to the club.
你跟Robert说我们去俱乐部
I have a very poor senseof direction.
我方向感极差
You have a very poor senseof decorum.
你的礼貌才差
I never use that word.I'm not sure what it means.
我从不用那个字，把握不好意思
- At the club we'd be with other people.- You're right.
- 在俱乐部就得跟其他人在一起- 说对了
Here we are,in the sunshine...
而我们在这里，在阳光里...
eating fish, literallyjust off the boat...
吃着刚从船上打来的鱼...
when we could be squashed between LordTubby and Cecil the Scintillating...
代替了在Tubby大人和光彩照人的 Cecil中间挤着……
listening to one or theother gripe about his digestion...
听他们抱怨自己的消化病
while the Contessa, in acounter-medley, wails that...
同时混杂着女爵爷哀号……
Alessandra cares more for...
Alessandra比关心自己...
the mating habits of theblue bellied finch...
还更关心蓝腹鸟交配习惯...
than those of her own species,and the widow Plymdale...
Plymdale寡妇转着怪异的眼睛...
bats her eyes logingly everypassing pair of trou.
死盯着别人的裤子
All of which is time wellspent in my book.
那是我看书时打发的时光
So, yes, I take your point.
所以，是的，我接受你的意见
I can't argue. At the club, we'dbe with other people.
我无法争辩，在俱乐部我们得跟其他人一起
Afraid we'll be seen?
害怕我们被发现吗?
Set the chins wagging?
给人嚼舌根?
Do you know what I findworse than being talked about?
你知道我发现比被人嚼舌根更可怕的是什么?
Not being talked about at all.
根本不被人谈起
Mrs Erlynne will see you upstairs.
Erlynne太太在楼上见你
In her bedroom.
在她卧室
Thank you. I won't be long.
谢谢，我不会久呆
"I won't be long."
"我不会久呆"
This is expensive.
这很贵
- Nothing but the best for you.- I know, I paid for it.
- 只给你最好的- 我知道，是我付的钱
Well, there is that.
都在那了
Should we be drinking thisearly in the day?
我们该这么早就喝酒吗?
Well, somewhere in the worldit's very late.
世界上的某地现在很晚了
I don't want you thinkingI make a habit of this.
我不想让你觉得这样成习惯了
Is that why you look so guilty?
那是你看上去内疚的原因吗?
I don't like lying to her.
我不喜欢跟她说谎
I should go.She's only gone to lunch.
我得走了，她只是去吃饭
This is all the cashI have right now.
这是我现在所有的现金
I'll set you up with an account.
我会给你建个账号
You can draw on it directly.
你就可以直接提取了
I met Meg.
我遇到Meg了
It was by chance.
是个巧遇
It's all right,she had no idea who I was.
没事的，她不知道我是谁
You spoke to her?
你跟她说话了吗?
Yes, for a minute.She's very pretty.
对，很短，她很漂亮
How did you two meet?Was it love at first sight?
你们俩怎么遇上的?是一见钟情吗?
I have to go.
我得走了
I'm curious. It's only natural.
我好奇，很自然的
There's no pointto these questions.
这些问题没意义
- Do you love her?- Very much.
- 你爱她吗?- 很爱
I'd rather cut off my armthan see Meg hurt.
我宁可断臂也不想让Meg受伤
Are you protecting her oryour reputation?
你是在保护她还是保护你的名声?
You don't know me at all.
你对我一无所知
Did he work on yourwedding night?
他在你们的新婚之夜也工作吗?
He's very conscientiousand I respect him for it.
他很尽责，我为此而敬重他
Suppose it wasn't work,suppose he had a mistress.
假设不是因为工作，假设他有情妇
Well, I couldn't respect that.
哦，那我可不敬重了
Once a wife's been betrayed...
一旦妻子遭背叛...
she has the freedom todo likewise.
她就有依样做的理由
No, that would make her as badas her husband, wouldn't it?
不，那岂不让她跟那丈夫一样坏了吗?
Modern marriage thrives onmutual deception.
现代婚姻因彼此欺骗而兴旺
We are completely honestwith each other.
我们彼此完全忠诚
You should makehim your model.
你该以他为榜样
I intend to.From this moment on.
我正打算，从现在开始
Don't you like it?
你不喜欢吗?
Oh, I'm saving it for Robert.He loves figs.
哦，我给Robert留着，他喜欢无花果
Share mine, then.
那吃我的吧
Can we go to thetelegraph office?
我们能去电报局吗?
He probably hasn't eaten.
他可能还没吃东西呢
Alberto? Fabrizio?
Oh, what's his name?
哦，他叫什么?
Mario?
Barman.
酒保
Whisky.
威士忌
And another thing, your Mrs Erlynnehas no principles at all.
另外, 你的Erlynne太太完全没有原则
I like people more than principles.
我喜欢人甚于原则
And people without principles,even better.
没原则的人就更好了
But Lord Augustus, she onlywants you for your money.
但是Augustus大人她只是要你的钱啊
Now why shouldn't she?It's my best asset.
她干嘛不能？那是我最好的资产
Old-ish, fat-ish,absolutely no brain...
又老又胖，完全无脑
heaps and heaps of banknotes.
成堆的钞票
No need toput yourself down, Tuppy.
并不需要贬低自己，Tuppy
Your friends can always do that.
让你的朋友们来嘛
Down by the marina, strolling along,pretty as you please...
在码头，一起徘徊，跟你一样美……
guess who I saw withLord Darlington?
猜我看见谁跟Darlington大人在一起?
They haven't seen him today.
他们今天没看见他
Do you know wheremy husband is?
你知道我丈夫在哪吗?
I thought he leftafter you, signora.
我以为他跟你一起走了，女士
Robert?
How was lunch?
午饭怎样?
We went to the telegraph office.Where were you?
我们去电报局了，你去哪了?
Well, we must have justmissed each other.
我们也许刚巧错过了
Now I see uncle.He's with the american woman.
现在我看见叔叔了他跟那美国女人在一起
Too much rouge and notenough clothing.
口红过多，衣服过少
She's appealing to the worstin the poor man.
她使尽招数引诱那可怜的男人
It's what women do best.
那是女人的拿手好戏
I heard she left New Yorkwithout paying her hotel bill.
我听说她离开New York连酒店的帐都没付
Quite a scandal.
真是个丑闻
- Who? Someone you know?- Someone you don't want to know.
- 谁? 你认识的人吗?- 是个你不想认识的人
No. Steer clear.
不，Steer Clear
She's the onewith Lord Augustus.
她就是跟Augustus大人在一起的
You've met Mrs Erlynne,haven't you?
你已经认识Erlynne太太了，是吧？
- No.- But I've seen you.
- 没有.- 可我看见你了
Oh, was that your foot?
哦，那是你的脚吗?
Wherever do you findshoes to fit?
你到哪去找合脚的鞋啊?
My feet are in perfect proportionto the rest of me.
我的脚跟我身体其他部分很成比例
Oh, yes, of course.
哦，是的，当然
Though they have a habit of findingthemselves in peculiar places.
尽管他们有在奇特的地方出现的习惯
Those people arestaring right at us.
那些人在盯着我们看呢
Who?
谁?
Don't worry about them.
别理会他们
It's my brother's wife andher friend, Lady Plymdale.
那是我哥哥的妻子和她的朋友Plymdale女士
Lord Plymdale passed onlast year. Liver, I think.
Plymdale大人去年死了，肝，我想
- Poor woman.- Oh, yes, very sad.
- 可怜的女人- 哦，是的，很悲惨
Her hair turned quitegold with grief.
因为伤心，她的头发越发的金色了
Erlynne, that's right.She came into some money.
Erlynne, 对了，她有了一些进项
- I made an investment for her.- An inheritance, I suppose?
- 我为她管理投资- 是遗产吧，我猜?
The woman in the shop.I told you, remember?
商店里的女人，我告诉过你的，记得吗?
The dress?
套装?
No, back and almost no front.You could see everything.
不，后背，几乎没有前片你什么都能看见
It was indecent.
很不像样
You're just not used toItalian fashions, that's all.
你只是不习惯意大利时装而已
No, I'm sure your wife ison the mark.
我觉得你妻子挺合拍的
Mrs Erlynne is anotorious Jezebel.
Erlynne太太是个声名狼藉的无耻女人
That's a slanderous statement. If youcan't back it up, I wouldn't repeat it.
那是诽谤，如果你不收回，我不会重复
Robert always gives everybodythe benefit of the doubt.
Robert总是给不随便评价他人的
I'm sorry, I just don't like gossip.
对不起，我只是不喜欢流言
Gossip's all right, it's themoralising that's in poor taste.
流言没什么，这是口味低下的布道
She's got her eye on me,if you know what I mean.
她看上我了，你该懂我意思
So I wouldn't worry about what theysay, it's all cats in a bag.
所以我根本不担心他们说什么不过是囊中之物吧了
Why, what do they say about me?
怎么了，他们怎么说我的？
That I'm a wanton woman?
说我是荡妇?
Brazen - with a past.
厚颜无耻，背景复杂
A brazen woman.Oh, dear.
一个厚颜无耻的女人，哦，我的天啊
You're very brazen yourselfto be seen in my company.
由我陪伴的你才真是厚颜无耻呢
I've got a bit of a pastmyself you know.
我也有个复杂的背景啊
Married and divorced twice.
结婚离婚了两次
Every experience is of value andwhatever you say...
每个经历都有价值
about marriage it certainlyis an experience.
无论你怎么讲究婚姻都肯定是有价值的
People call somethingan experience...
当人们讲究经历的时候...
They usually meanit was a mistake.
他们多半说的是错误
I couldn't agree more.
我无任同意
We've all got a couple ofskeletons in the closet.
我们都在储藏间里藏着几具骷髅
If they're going to rattle,they may as well dance.
如果他们要喋喋不休还不如干脆跳舞
You're absolutely right.
你完全正确
Whenever anyone agrees with me,I'm sure I must be wrong.
只要有人赞同我我一定错了
You like to be theodd man out, do you?
你喜欢作最后一个剩下的人，是吧?
I'll never understand women.
我从来就不能理解女人
Women don't want to be understood,they want to be loved.
女人不需要人理解，只需要人爱
You're dead wrong on that.
你这就大错了
You're very understanding.
你真善解人意
That girl in lilac,do you know her?
戴丁香花的女人，你认识吗?
Oh, yes, it's Robert's wife.
哦，是的，那是Robert的妻子
All lovey-dovey,very charming.
很可爱，很迷人
I wish she'd stop staring at me.
我希望她别再盯着我了
She isn't at all.
她没有
Those women must begiving her an earful.
那些女人肯定在给她进言呢
- You mustn't mind.- I don't, as a rule.
- 你别介意- 按照惯例，我没有
Look, it's terribly stuffy in here,I can hardly breathe.
你看，这很乏味，我都不能喘气了
Shall we go? Would you mind?
我们走吧，你介意吗？
I can't think of anythingI'd mind less.
我根本一点都不介意
Good.
好
I can't believe it - she's got him!
我不敢相信，她钓上他了
Poor Tuppy.
可怜的Tuppy
Shall I get a taxi?
我叫个出租车吧?
- Could we walk?- Why not.
- 可以走路吗?- 为何不呢
Beautiful city.
漂亮的城市
The Romans call it"The Land of the Sirens..."
罗马人叫它"妖妇之城"
from Homer's Odyssey.
出自荷马的《奥德赛》
Is that so? Aren't you clever?
真的吗?你真聪明
- I read it somewhere.- I like a good read myself.
- 我在哪里读到的- 我也喜欢阅读
Nothing too laborious. I don't wantto tamper with natural ignorance.
别太累，我不想影响自然的无知
- It's the key to happiness.- Do you really think so?
- 是快乐的钥匙- 你真那么想吗?
Absolutely. Good health,it's important, but...
绝对是，健康，很重要...
ignorance is the key. Too muchknowledge and you're doomed.
无知是钥匙，太多知识你就被限制住了
Well, here we are.
嗯，到了
Aren't you going to invite mein for a nightcap?
你都不邀请我进睡前酒吗?
The sirens were said to behalf woman, half monster.
传说中的妖妇是半人半魔
They lured the sailors withtheir songs.
她们用歌声引诱水手
The ships crashed on therocks and the men all drowned.
船只触礁，水手溺水
Oh, let's go in. You can tell memore about it.
哦，进去吧，你再多告诉我一些
Poor Lady Plymdale, I think shereally likes Tuppy.
可怜的Plymdale女士,我觉得她是真喜欢Tuppy
- Where do you suppose they went?- Who?
- 你觉得他们去哪里了?- 谁?
Tuppy and Mrs Erlynne.
Tuppy 和Erlynne太太
Probably back to her apartment.
可能回她住所了
Probably.
可能
Do you think he'll inviteher to my party?
你觉得他会邀请她参加我的舞会吗?
I'll make sure he doesn't.
我会确保他不能
- Well, don't be mean about it.- No, of course not.
- 别太刻薄了- 不，当然不会
It's just I don't want anyoneto be uncomfortable, you know?
只是我不想让任何人尴尬，明白吗?
Someone like that makesthings awkward.
那样的事会令局面很难受
You can say it's a small party.Private, just friends.
你就说是个小舞会，只是些朋友而已
- No investors.- All right.
- 没有投资人- 好
It's not just girl gossip. JohnDarlington knows all abou it.
那不只是女孩的流言，JohnDarlington 知道所有情况
He said her friend isa married man.
他说她的朋友是个已婚男人
It's disgusting.
真令人厌恶
You know what, people like tohear themselves talk.
你知道吗，人们喜欢听自己讲话
- Why do you insist on defending her?- I'm not defending her.
- 你干嘛要坚持为她辩护?- 我没替她辩护
Yes, you are.
你有
Let's drop it.
我们别说了
It's just... Should yoube helping her invest?
只是……你该替她管理投资吗?
Everyone knows how shecame into the money.
所有人都知道她钱的来路
New topic.
新话题
Close your eyes.
闭眼
- Robert?- Close your eyes.
- Robert?- 闭眼
It's after midnight.Happy birthday.
已经过午夜了生日快乐
- It's beautiful.- Do you like it?
- 真美- 你喜欢吗?
Thank you.
谢谢
- I love you.- I love you, too.
- 我爱你- 我也爱你
Oh, my!
哦，天啊
- Thank you.- Don't mention it.
- 谢谢- 别提了
You like it?
你喜欢吗?
Food is the rock...
食物是岩石...
on which we build.
由我们创造
No love is pure and simpleas the love of food.
没有爱象食物一样纯洁而简单
Love is rarely pure, Lord Augustus.And never simple.
爱少有纯洁，Augustus大人而且从不简单
I don't think you've beenin love, Mrs Erlynne.
我不认为你曾爱过，Erlynne太太
You may presumeto call me Stella...
你可以假称我Stella...
but don't presumeto know my heart.
但别假装你知道我的心
For your information,I'm always in love.
根据你的情报，我永远都在恋爱
Good. Excellent attitude.And you're beautiful.
好，出色的态度，而且你很美
Smart, too. Smarter than me,I expect, but...
也精明，比我精明，我希望……
that's not saying much,I'm afraid.
希望没说太多
No, I think I'll do very wellto marry you.
不，我觉得如果跟你结婚我会很好的
How very practical.
多实际啊
I've begun too many romancesout of sentiment.
我开始过太多不涉及情感的浪漫了
They always end in settlement.
最终都以结算为结局
I could listen to you all night,Lord Augustus.
我可以整夜听你倾诉Augustus大人
Tuppy, please.
请叫我Tuppy
You'll think about my offer?
你会考虑我的提议吗?
Men don't marry women like me.
男人不跟我这样的女人结婚的
There aren't any women like you.
那是因为没有你这样的女人
At least, not among the womenI've met, and I've met my share.
至少我认识的人里面没有我遇到可以分享的了
I was married - I didn't take to it.
我曾结婚，但不喜欢
People change. You mightfeel differently.
人会变，你会感受到不同的
When I think of it, I thinkof a room...
当我想到的时候我想到
where you can't open a window.
一个不能开窗的房间
Where there is no window.
因为没有窗户
Every day you wake upand the room is smaller.
每天醒来，你发现房间又变小了
You don't notice, not at first.It happens slowly.
你不会注意，开始不会逐渐发生
In inches.
一点点的
Then one morning,you open your eyes...
然后某天早晨你睁眼发现...
and the room is so small...
房间已经小的...
you can't move.
你无法腾挪了
You can't take a breath.
无法呼吸
You have to get out.
你不得不逃走
You can't think of anything else.
你什么事都无法想
Or anyone else.
什么人都无法想
You married the wrong man,that's all.
你只是嫁错了人
He married the wrong woman.
他娶错了人
It's late.
很晚了
It's time for bed.
该上床了
Sleep.
睡觉
"...Perchance to dream".
"偶然的梦境"
That's the bard, you know.I'm a bit of a reader myself.
是吟游诗人，你知道我自己也读过点书的
So you said. Goodnight, Tuppy.
照你说的，晚安，Tuppy
I hate the taste of tobacco.
我讨厌烟草味
Well - that's it then.
好，就这样
I quit. On the spot.
我戒了，当场
What else can I tell you?
我还能告诉你什么?
I'm a very rich man, you know.
我是个非常富有的人，你知道
You're a very nice man.
你是个非常好的人
Go to bed.
上床吧
You know, I'm glad I quit.
你知道，我很高兴戒烟了
Filthy habit, really.
肮脏的习惯，真的
Goodnight.
晚安
Is there going to be a lion tamer,or is it just the usual clowns?
是驯狮人或只是普通的小丑?
Robert was afraid it might rain.
Robert害怕会下雨呢
I just wanted a few people for dinnerbut he said you are only 21 once.
我本来只想几个人吃饭但他说你一生只得一次21岁
I know plenty of women who, of theirown accord, turn 35 year after year.
我认识很多女人，按照她们的记录年年都过35
I'm sure you can be 21 as many times.
我肯定你可以21岁很多年
I think it's silly to lie about your age.
我觉得对于岁数撒谎很蠢
- You have no redeeming vices.- I hope not.
- 你没有补偿的恶习- 我希望没有
Happy Birthday.
生日快乐
The invitation said no gifts.
邀请信上写了不要礼物
That's why I brought it now.
所以我现在把它带来了
It's too expensive. I know youdon't mean anything by it, but...
这太贵了，我知道你没什么意思...
it wouldn't look right.
但看上去不对
Gold looks right with everything.Just wear it. No-one has to know.
金子衬什么都行，戴上就是了不需要人知道
I'd know.
我知道
I do mean something by it.
我可意味深长
- Please...- It's a gift of friendship, Maggie.
- 拜托...- 这是友谊的礼物, Maggie
You'll hurt me deeply if you refuse.
如果你拒绝就太伤我了
Now look what you've made me do.
看看你现在逼的我
A little sincerity can be a verydangerous thing.
一点真诚会成为很危险的事
Any more could be fatal.
再来点就致命了
Just take the damn thing beforeI die and ruin your terrace.
在我死在你露台上前赶紧把这该死的玩艺接过去吧
It's very pretty. Thank you.
很美，谢谢你
Where's Robert? Off sendinganother telegram?
Robert在哪? 又发电报去了吗？
Signora, the florist is waitingfor his money.
女主人，花匠在等着拿工钱
I'll have to get it fromMr Windemere.
我得跟Windemere先生拿
Can he come back later?
他能呆会儿再来吗?
Has Robert a cheque-bookin his office?
Robert 在办公室不是有支票本吗？
- Can you sign on the account?- Ah, yes, of course.
- 你能在账户签单吗?- 啊，是的，当然
Tell him to wait.I'll see you tonight.
让他等一下我们今晚见了
People don't always behavethe way we expect.
人们并不总象我们希望的那样守规矩
Just the opposite. The truth is Idon't want to see you hurt.
其实正相反，事实是我不希望看到你受伤
What are you talking about?
你说什么呢?
You may need a friendone of these days.
这些日子你或许需要个朋友
When you do, I'm here.Will you remember that?
当你需要的时候，我在这里你会记得吗?
Yes, of course.
是，当然
I came as quickly as I could.
我尽快赶来了
We're all so distressed over it.
我们都很悲伤
But you mustn't take it personally.
可你不该太责备自己了
Mrs Erlynne is one ofthose women...
Erlynne太太是那种...
that attract men like abee to a flame.
火焰吸引蜜蜂一样吸引男人的女人
- A moth.- Bee to a moth.
- 是飞蛾- 飞蛾吸引蜜蜂